Guide to the Fidelis Zitterbart Manuscripts, 1868-1915 SC.1967.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Fidelis Zitterbart Manuscripts
1868-1915
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Zitterbart, Fidelis
SC.1967.02
22 Linear Feet (85 document boxes)
Fidelis Zitterbart was an active music teacher, performer, and composer from the 1860s through his death in 1915. He was also a member of the New York Theatre orchestra, first violinist with the Theodore Thomas Orchestra, concertmaster of the Strakosch Opera orchestra, and a member of the Brooklyn and New York Philharmonic societies. This collection contains Zitterbart's manuscript compositions for many different musical genres. Digital reproductions are online.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of the collection are available online.
Previous Citation
Fidelis Zitterbart Manuscripts, 1868-1915, SC.1967.02, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Acquisition Information
Gift of Ralph Zitterbart in May 1960.
Biography
Fidelis Zitterbart was born April 9, 1845 in Pittsburgh, Pa., to Fidelis Sr. and Frederica Zitterbart. His father was well-known as a violinist, but also as a conductor and composer who came to the United States as a member of a troupe of instrumentalists from Prague, one of many European musical organizations who saw in this country an untapped audience. When this troupe was disbanded in 1837 without ever completing its tour, Fidelis Sr., after stays in New York and New Orleans, decided to settle in Pittsburgh. The family occupied a small house on 10th Street in Pittsburgh's South Side neighborhood, where Fidelis Jr. was born; his father was his first music teacher. At age 9, Fidelis Jr. became one of the violinists in his father's orchestra, and at this time began to put his musical ideas on paper.
Fidelis Jr. worked with local teachers until the age of 16, when like many musical prodigies, he was sent to Europe to continue his studies. Departing New York in 1861, he travelled to Dresden to continue his violin studies with François Schubert (1808-1878), and theory and keyboard with Julius Rühlmann (1816-1877). Fidelis returned to the United States in 1863 and stayed in New York City where he was a member of several premier musical organizations, including his father's New York Theatre orchestra, first violinist with the Theodore Thomas Orchestra, concertmaster of the Strakosch Opera orchestra, and a member of the Brooklyn and New York Philharmonic societies.
In 1873, Fidelis returned to Pittsburgh as an instructor at Andrew Williams's American Conservatory of Music, located at 41 Fifth Avenue in Downtown Pittsburgh. When the school fell on hard times and closed, Zitterbart opened his own school in the same location, acting as teacher, performer, and composer. He was highly itinerant in Pittsburgh as to dwelling places: he maintained houses in the Hill District (on Crawford and Reed Streets [1874-1877]); Uptown (on Pride and Marion Streets [1878-1911]; in Shadyside (on Summerlea Street [1912-1913]; and finally in Highland Park on North Highland Avenue [1915]. He passed away on August 30, 1915 and was interred in Allegheny Cemetery.
Scope and Content Notes
The collection contains approximately 1,500 music compositions, all in Fidelis Zitterbart's hand. Many of the scores feature Zitterbart's personal calligraphy in the noting of titles, often with pasted-over images that were evocative of the music's meaning to the composer. The scores are notated in both blue and black ink and sometimes in pencil, on standard 14-stave lined sheets in upright format, or in oblong format. Emendations by the composer appear in ink and/or pencil. The paper, produced in the late nineteenth- and early-twentieth centuries is acidic, often brittle. The collection has been digitized to allow for greater access to researchers as well as to limit the need to access the fragile original materials. Few, if any of the works in the collection were ever commercially published. In processing this collection, we respected the original order in which the manuscripts were received. However, whenever a work is in a particular musical genre (suites, sonatas, duos, quartets, etc.) and is also numbered by the composer, we rearranged these items to bring them together for ease of discoverability.
Arrangement
The following musical genres may be found in the box ranges listed:
1. Concertos (Violin): Box 32
2. Duets (Strings and Winds): Box 4–6
3. Etudes (Piano): Box 34–35
4. Nocturnes (Piano): Box 37
5. Quartets (Piano and Strings): Box 13–16
6. Quartets (Strings): Box 16–22
7. Quintets (Strings): Box 23–24
8. Quintets (Piano and Strings): Box 24–26
9. Sonatas (Piano): Box 36
10. Sonatas (One String Instrument and Piano): Box 27–30
11. Suites (Piano): Box 1
12. Suites (One or more instruments and piano): Box 2–3
13. Trios (Various Instrumental Combinations): Box 6–13
14. Waltzes (Piano): Box 33
Orchestra music -- Scores and parts; Symphonic poems; Music -- Manuscripts; Chamber music -- Scores and parts; Composers -- Pittsburgh, Pa.; Zitterbart, Fidelis
- Suite No. 1 for Solo Piano in C Major, 10 p. of music (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Content Notes
  On caption: Classic Suite in C major. Contents: Prelude -- Gavotte -- Canzonetta -- Minuet-Pastorale -- Finale: Marcia maestoso.
- Suite No. 2 The Nursery for Solo Piano in F Major, 12 p. of music (Box 1, Folder 2)
  At head of title: To Beatrice and Cedric Braun. Movements based on nursery rhymes. Contents: 1. Jack and Jill -- 2. Little pig went to the market -- 3. Little Bo Peep -- 4. Ba ba black sheep -- 5. Mother Goose -- 6. Cinderella's valse.
- Suite No. 3 Souvenier de Schumann for Solo Piano in A Major, April 5, 1900; 7 p. of music (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Illustration of Robert Schumann pasted on cover.
- Suite No. 4 for Solo Piano in F Minor, April 5, 1900; 12 p. of music (Box 1, Folder 4)
  At head of title: To Mrs. C. Zitterbart. Contents: Introduzione quasi praeludio -- Canzonetta -- Minuet -- Meditation -- Finale. Tema et uno variatione et scherzo vivace.
- Suite No. 5 Music's Phases by C. Tulloch for Solo Piano in E-flat Major, November 27, 1902; 15 p. of music (Box 1, Folder 5)
  The number "5" pasted on cover. Contents: 1. Introductione (Moderato-con-moto et molto-esspressione) -- 2. Cradle song (Adagio-con-moto et cantabile) -- 3. Capriccio (Presto) -- 4. Marcia eroica -- 5. Marcia funebre -- 6. Religioso fantastique -- 7. Finale (Moderato-con grazioso et Allegro-spiritoso).
- Suite No. 5 for Solo Piano in A Minor, 11 p. of music (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Contents: 1. Praeludio in A minor -- 2. Canzonetta -- 3. Minuet: The antique -- 4. Romance -- 5. Finale: Scherzo (presstissimo).
- Suite No. 6 The Music of the Sea for Solo Piano in C# Minor, 18 p. of music (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Photo of unidentified beach pasted on cover.
- Suite No. 6 Christmas for Solo Piano, December 14, 1902; 8 p. of music (Box 1, Folder 8)
  The number "6" pasted on cover. At head of title: To Mrs. Agnes Braun. Contents: 1. Introductione: Moderato-maestoso -- 2. Under the magnolia -- 3. Valse impromptu (La esmeralda) -- 4. Finale.
- Suite No. 7 Market Suite for Solo Piano in A Minor, April 16, 1900; 19 p. of music (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Melodic subjects for each movement given in notes on caption: 1. -a-b-b-a-g-e -- 2. B-e-e-f -- 3. E-g-g(s) -- 4. C-a-f-é.
- Suite No. 8 Pocohontas for Solo Piano in Ab Major, April 23, 1900; 17 p. of music (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Suite No. 9 Gems for Solo Piano in Bb Minor, 24 p. of music (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Contents: Praeludio -- Allegretto -- Allegro-militaire -- Valse (for the left hand alone) -- Finale. Allegro appassionato: The fairy council.
- Suite No. 10 American for Solo Piano in Eb Major, May 1 1900; 15 p. of music (Box 1, Folder 12)
  At head of title: To William Speer.
- Suite No. 11 Romantique for Solo Piano in Db Major, 1906?; 19 p. of music (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Two copies, one numbered, the other unnumbered. At end of 1st copy is pencil manuscript (5 p.) for Murmering Waves: morceau de viola, dated July 20th, 1906. For viola and piano. Original title was Wispering Waves, but "Wispering" is crossed out and "Murmering" written in black ink above. Contents: Reverie de nuit -- Allegro con moto et appassionato -- Adagio amoroso et affettuoso -- Allegro appassionato -- Finale: Impromptu (una momento).
- Suite No. 12 for Solo Piano in B Minor, May 1 1900; 19 p. of music (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Numerous corrections in pencil and with pasteovers in the 2nd movement. Contents: Wandering minstrel -- Idyll -- Fughetta; Scherzo-Presstissimo -- Finale. Thema con variatione (originale).
- Suite No. 13 for Solo Piano in C# Minor, 16 p. of music (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Contents:Praeludio -- Canzonetta -- Barcarolle -- Intermezzo -- Finale. Tarantella.
- Suite No. 14 for Solo Piano in Eb Major, 12 p. of music (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Contents: Jagdstück (in Eb major) -- Adagio pathetique (in F minor) -- Impromptu. Allegro agitato -- Romance -- Finale. Scherzo-Presto.
- Suite No. 15 for Solo Piano in E Major, July 10, 1902; 21 p. of music (Box 1, Folder 17)
  At head of title: To Mrs. Eva Hayes Huselton. Contents: Meditation -- Polonaise grande -- Allegro agitato et passione -- Intermedietto -- Barcarolle: plaintive.
- Suite No. 16 for Solo Piano in A Minor, June 22, 1904; 10 p. of music (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Photocopy of manuscript. Contents: 1. Praeludio -- 2. Canzonetta -- 3. Scherzo presto -- 4. Romanza -- 5. Finale: Marcia heroique
- Suite No. 17 for Solo Piano in A Minor, October 15, 1906; 11 p. of music (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Capital letters spelling SUITE pasted on cover. Contents: Praeludio -- Canzonetta -- A la mazurka brillante et moderne -- Finale. Tarantella.
- Suite No. 1 Suite Fantasique for Violin and Piano in C# Minor, May 12, 1900; 1 score (23 p.) and violin part (9 p.) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  The number "1" pasted on cover. "#666" written in pencil on cover. At head of title: To Mrs. Helen Deming of Worcester, Mass.
  - Suite No. 1 Suite Fantasique - Score, May 12, 1900; 1.
  - Suite No. 1 Suite Fantasique - Parts: Violin, May 12, 1900; 2.
- Suite No. 2 Southern Suite for Violin and Piano in Bb Major, 1 score (20 p.) and violin part (7 p.) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  The number "2" pasted on cover. "#665" written in pencil on cover. On cover and caption: To Miss Adalaide Zitterbart. Contents: 1. Moderato con moto -- 2. Allegro con moto et mystyrioso (At Savannah)-- 3. Andante Meditation: Impressions-- 4. Finale, Allegro vigoroso (At New Orleans).
  - Suite No. 2 Southern Suite - Score, 1.
  - Suite No. 2 Southern Suite - Parts: Violin, 2.
- Suite No. 3 for Violin and Piano in Bb Major, November 2, 1900; 1 score (16 p.) and violin part (6 p.) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  The number "3" pasted on cover. "#664" written in pencil on cover.
  - Suite No. 3 - Score, November 2, 1900; 1.
  - Suite No. 3 - Parts: Violin, November 2, 1900; 2.
- Suite No. 4 Southern Suite for Violin and Piano in Eb Major, March 10, 1900; 1 score (19 p.) and violin part (8 p.) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  The number "4" pasted on cover. "#663" written in pencil on cover. At head of title: To Miss Helen Zitterbart. Photograph of a child (Helen Zitterbart?) pasted on cover.
  - Suite No. 4 Southern Suite - Score, March 10, 1900; 1.
  - Suite No. 4 Southern Suite - Parts: Violin, March 10, 1900; 2.
- Suite No. 5 for Violin and Piano in A Minor, December 20, 1900; 1 score (16 p.) and violin part, (7 p.) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  The number "5" pasted on cover. "#668" written in pencil on cover and part. Contents: 1. Allegro Apassianato -- 2. Adagio Amoroso -- 3. Minuet Grazioso -- 4. Allegro Moderato
  - Suite No. 5 - Score, December 20, 1900; 1.
  - Suite No. 5 - Parts: Violin, December 20, 1900; 2.
- Suite No. 6 for Violin and Piano in D Minor, January 14, 1901; 1 score (26 p.) and violin part (7 p.) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  The number "6" pasted on cover and part. "#669" written in pencil on cover and part.
  - Suite No. 6 - Score, January 14, 1901; 1.
  - Suite No. 6 - Parts: Violin, January 14, 1901; 2.
- Suite No. 7 for Violin and Piano in E Minor, November 26, 1901; 1 score (22 p.) and vioin part (7 p.) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  The number "7" pasted on cover and part. "#670" written in pencil on cover and part.
  - Suite No. 7 - Score, November 26, 1901; 1.
  - Suite No. 7 - Parts: Violin, November 26, 1901; 2.
- Suite No. 8 Pastorale, Scenes of Rose Point for Violin and Piano in D Major, August 7, 1902; 1 score (24 p.) and violin part (9 p.) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  The number "8" pasted on cover. "#671" written in pencil on cover and part. At head of titel: To Mr. Harry Hetzel and William Speer. Contents: 1. The country road -- 2. The Needle Falls -- 3. Moderato legiero (Country surroundings) -- 4. Adagio (The old homestead) -- 5. Finale: Allegro spiritoso (Homeward bound). Contains two copies of violin part.
  - Suite No. 8 Pastorale, Scenes of Rose Point - Score, August 7, 1902; 1.
  - Suite No. 8 Pastorale, Scenes of Rose Point - Parts: Violin (two copies), August 7, 1902; 2.
- Suite No. 10 Marmie for Violin and Piano in G Major, May 15, 1912; 1 score (23 p.) and violin part (7 p.) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  The number "10" and "#673" written in pencil on cover. Subtitle on score: Morceau de salon. Contents: 1. Song of the brook (Allegro con moto) -- 2. Introduction, recitativo-scherzo-presto -- 3. Adagio-pathetique e harmoniosa -- 4. Finale: Allegro spiritoso.
  - Suite No. 10 Marmie - Score, May 15, 1912; 1.
  - Suite No. 10 Marmie - Parts: Violin, May 15, 1912; 2.
- Suite No. 11 for Violin and Piano in G Major, August 28, 1914; 1 score (25 p.) and violin part (9 p.) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  The number "11" and "#674" written in pencil on cover.
  - Suite No. 11 - Score, August 28, 1914; 1.
  - Suite No. 11 - Parts: Violin, August 28, 1914; 2.
- Suite No. 12 Pastoral Suite for Violin and Piano in A Major, July 15, 1914; 1 score (28 p.) and violin part (8 p.) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  The number "12" and "#675" written in pencil on cover. On cover and t.p.: To Mr. and Mrs. James L. Black. Illustrations on t.p. and caption of each movement pasted in. Poem with 1st line: Sigh of the slumbering wood pasted on caption of movement 4. Location: Piqua, Ohio
  - Suite No. 12 Pastoral Suite - Score, July 15, 1914; 1.
  - Suite No. 12 Pastoral Suite - Parts: Violin, July 15, 1914; 2.
- Suite for Violin and Piano in Bb Major, July 15, 1911; 1 score (18 p.) and violin part (6 p.) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  The number "9" written in on cover and part. Contents: Praeludio -- Allegro spiritoso -- Canzonetta -- Allegro assai.
  - Suite for Violin and Piano in Bb Major - Score, July 15, 1911; 1.
  - Suite for Violin and Piano in Bb Major - Parts: Violin, July 15, 1911; 2.
- Suite No. 38 for Viola and Piano in C Major, August 30, 1911; 5 scores ([30] p.) 5 parts (Box 2, Folder 13)
  The number "38" written in red pencil on scores. Each movement has its own score and part. Dates of composition given on each movement. Contents: 1. Adagio amoroso (8/15/1911) -- 2. The imp of the swamp (8/23/1911) -- 3. Improvisation (8/26/1911) -- 4. Reflection (8/30/1911) -- 5. The vision (8/31/1911).
  - Suite No. 38 - Scores, August 30, 1911; 1.
  - Suite No. 38 - Parts: Viola, August 30, 1911; 2.
- Suite No. 7 for Violoncello et Piano in D Minor, 1 score (23 p. ) and cello part (7 p.) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  The number "7" pasted in on score and part. The number "396" penciled in on score. The number "660" penciled in on violoncello part.
  - Suite No. 7 - Score, 1.
  - Suite No. 7 - Parts: Violoncello, 2.
- Suite No. 8 for Flute and Piano in B Minor, September 11, 1902; 1 score (12 p.) and flute part (5 p.) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  The number "8" pasted in on cover, score and part.
  - Suite No. 8 - Score, September 11, 1902; 1.
  - Suite No. 8 - Parts: Flute, September 11, 1902; 2.
- Suite No. 16 Romantic for Violin, Flute, and Piano in F Major, December 21, 1904; 1 score (25 p. ), violin part (6 p.), and flute part (6 p.) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  The number "16" pasted in on cover, t.p. and parts. The number "1175" penciled in on cover. Illustrations on cover: one of a young woman, and the other of trees and a pond.
  - Suite No. 16 Romantic - Score, December 21, 1904; 1.
  - Suite No. 16 Romantic - Parts: Violin, December 21, 1904; 2.
  - Suite No. 16 Romantic - Parts: Flute, December 21, 1904; 3.
- Suite No. 17 Fairy Stories for Violin, Flute, and Piano in A Major, December 25, 1904; 1 score (26 p.), violin part (6 p.), and flute part (5 p.) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  The number "17" pasted in on cover, score and parts. The number "180" penciled in on cover.
  - Suite No. 17 Fairy Stories - Score, December 25, 1904; 1.
  - Suite No. 17 Fairy Stories - Parts: Violin, December 25, 1904; 2.
  - Suite No. 17 Fairy Stories - Parts: Flute, December 25, 1904; 3.
- Suite No. 4 for Violine 1, Violine 2, Viola et Violincello in C Dur, violine 1 part (5 p.), violine 2 part (5 p.), viola part (5 p.), violincello part (5 p.) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  The number "140" written in pencil on cover.
  - Suite No. 4 - Parts: Violine 1, 1.
  - Suite No. 4 - Parts: Violine 2, 2.
  - Suite No. 4 - Parts: Viola, 3.
  - Suite No. 4 - Parts: Violoncello, 4.
- Suite [No.] 5 Rustic Fantasy for 2 Violins, 2 Violas, and Violoncello in Eb Major, October 6, 1902; violin 1 part (6 p.), violin 2 part (5 p.), viola 1 part (5 p.), viola 2 part (5 p.), violoncello part (5 p.) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Poetry written in blue ink pasted on the inside cover. Contents: The millpond -- The peasants outing -- The May Queen -- In field and meadow.
  - Suite [No.] 5 Rustic Fantasy - Parts: Violin 1, October 6, 1902; 1.
  - Suite [No.] 5 Rustic Fantasy - Parts: Violin 2, October 6, 1902; 2.
  - Suite [No.] 5 Rustic Fantasy - Parts: Viola 1, October 6, 1902; 3.
  - Suite [No.] 5 Rustic Fantasy - Parts: Viola 2, October 6, 1902; 4.
  - Suite [No.] 5 Rustic Fantasy - Parts: Violoncello, October 6, 1902; 5.
- Romantische Suite: [No.] 7: [for] Violine, Viola, Violoncello [and] Piano: [in C Major], December 1, 1885; violine 1 part (9 p.), violine 2 part (2 p.), viola part (7 p.), violincello part (6 p.) piano part (14 p.) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  The number "7" pasted in and written in red ink on caption. Composition date at end of piano part given as 12/18/1885. Contents: 1. Die Mühle -- 2. Der Gang nach dem Wald -- 3. In der Ruine -- 4. Nächtlicher Elfentanz -- 5. Der Hirtenknabe am Rach -- 6. Die Heinkehr des Fremden.
  - Romantische Suite: [No.] 7 - Parts: Violine 1, December 1, 1885; 1.
  - Romantische Suite: [No.] 7 - Parts: Violine 2, December 1, 1885; 2.
  - Romantische Suite: [No.] 7 - Parts: Viola, December 1, 1885; 3.
  - Romantische Suite: [No.] 7 - Parts: Violoncello, December 1, 1885; 4.
  - Romantische Suite: [No.] 7 - Parts: Piano, December 1, 1885; 5.
- Suite: The Maine: in 4 Numbers for Flute, Violin, Viola (and Violoncello), and Piano, [1898?]; 1 score (31 p.), flute part (5 p.), violin part (6 p.), viola part (5 p.), and violoncello part (5 p.) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  On cover: illustration of The Maine pasted in; on verso of t.p.: handwritten poem, Death, the spirit of the Maine. Violoncello part penciled in on score. Contents: The spirit of the Maine -- Pastorale -- Scherzo: sailors jolification on shore) -- The destruction and remorse.
  - Suite The Maine in 4 Numbers - Score, [1898?]; 1.
  - Suite The Maine in 4 Numbers - Parts: Flute, [1898?]; 2.
  - Suite The Maine in 4 Numbers - Parts: Violin, [1898?]; 3.
  - Suite The Maine in 4 Numbers - Parts: Viola, [1898?]; 4.
  - Suite The Maine in 4 Numbers - Parts: Violoncello, [1898?]; 5.
- Suite in D Minor The Lady of Shalott for 2 Flutes, 2 Violins, 2 Violas, Violoncello (et Oboe), and Piano, February 9, 1907; 1 score (37 p.), flute 1 part (4 p.), flute 2 part (4 p.), oboe part (4 p.), violin 1 part (6 p.), violin 2 part (5 p.), viola 1 part (5 p.), viola 2 part (5 p.), and violoncello part (5 p.) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  On caption: Poetry by Alfred Tennyson. At head of title: To Mrs. Agnes Braun. Flute and oboe parts penciled in on score.
  - Suite The Lady of Shalott - Score, February 9, 1907; 1.
  - Suite The Lady of Shalott - Parts: Flute 1, February 9, 1907; 2.
  - Suite The Lady of Shalott - Parts: Flute 2, February 9, 1907; 3.
  - Suite The Lady of Shalott - Parts: Oboe, February 9, 1907; 4.
  - Suite The Lady of Shalott - Parts: Violin 1, February 9, 1907; 5.
  - Suite The Lady of Shalott - Parts: Violin 2, February 9, 1907; 6.
  - Suite The Lady of Shalott - Parts: Viola 1, February 9, 1907; 7.
  - Suite The Lady of Shalott - Parts: Viola 2, February 9, 1907; 8.
  - Suite The Lady of Shalott - Parts: Violoncello, February 9, 1907; 9.
- Suite Fantastique in E Minor: The Legend of Sleepy Hollow (by Washington Irving): for 2 Violins, Viola, Flute, and Piano, February 19, 1903; 1 score (28 p.), flute part (5 p.), violin 1 part (5 p.), violin 2 part (5 p.), and viola part (5 p.) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Text on caption. Pasted in on cover, t.p. and parts: 27.
  - Suite Fantastique: The Legend of Sleepy Hollow (by Washington Irving) - Score, February 19, 1903; 1.
  - Suite Fantastique: The Legend of Sleepy Hollow (by Washington Irving) - Parts: Flute, February 19, 1903; 2.
  - Suite Fantastique: The Legend of Sleepy Hollow (by Washington Irving) - Parts: Violin 1, February 19, 1903; 3.
  - Suite Fantastique: The Legend of Sleepy Hollow (by Washington Irving) - Parts: Violin 2, February 19, 1903; 4.
  - Suite Fantastique: The Legend of Sleepy Hollow (by Washington Irving) - Parts: Viola, February 19, 1903; 5.
- Kleine Violin Duetten: für 2 Violinen: No. 1, September 8, 1883; violine 1 part (4 p.), and violine 2 part (4 p.) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  On wrapper: Duos 1-10; only no. 1-3 extant?
  - Kleine Violin Duetten: No. 1 - Parts: Violine 1, September 8, 1883; 1.
  - Kleine Violin Duetten: No. 1 - Parts: Violine 2, September 8, 1883; 2.
- Kleine Violin Duetten: für 2 Violinen: No. 2, September 10, 1883; violine 1 part (4 p.), and violine 2 part (4 p.) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Kleine Violin Duetten: No. 2 - Parts: Violine 1, September 10, 1883; 1.
  - Kleine Violin Duetten: No. 2 - Parts: Violine 2, September 10, 1883; 2.
- Kleine Violin Duetten: für 2 Violinen: No. 3, September 19, 1883; violine 1 part (4 p.), and violine 2 part (4 p.) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Kleine Violin Duetten: No. 3 - Parts: Violine 1, September 19, 1883; 1.
  - Kleine Violin Duetten: No. 3 - Parts: Violine 2, September 19, 1883; 2.
- Duo: [no.] 1 for 2 Violins in G Major, May 21, 1910; violin 1 part (8 p.), and violin 2 part (8 p.) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  The number "67" penciled in on cover.
  - Duo: [no.] 1 - Parts: Violin 1, May 21, 1910; 1.
  - Duo: [no.] 1 - Parts: Violin 2, May 21, 1910; 2.
- Duo: [no.] 2 for 2 Violins in F Major, May 25, 1910; violin 1 part (8 p.), and violin 2 part (7 p.) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  The number "68" penciled in on cover and parts.
  - Duo: [no.] 2 - Parts: Violin 1, May 25, 1910; 1.
  - Duo: [no.] 2 - Parts: Violin 2, May 25, 1910; 2.
- Duo: [no.] 3 for 2 Violins in C Major, May 28, 1910; violin 1 part (7 p.), and violin 2 part (7 p.) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  The number "69" penciled in on cover and parts.
  - Duo: [no.] 3 - Parts: Violin 1, May 28, 1910; 1.
  - Duo: [no.] 3 - Parts: Violin 2, May 28, 1910; 2.
- Duo: [no.] 4 for 2 Violins in G Minor, June 3, 1910; violin 1 part (9 p.), and violin 2 part (9 p.) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  The number "70" penciled in on cover and parts.
  - Duo: [no.] 4 - Parts: Violin 1, June 3, 1910; 1.
  - Duo: [no.] 4 - Parts: Violin 2, June 3, 1910; 2.
- Duo: [no.] 5 for 2 Violins in G Minor, June 10, 1910; violin 1 part (7 p.), and violin 2 part (7 p.) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  The number "71" penciled in on cover and parts.
  - Duo: [no.] 5 - Parts: Violin 1, June 10, 1910; 1.
  - Duo: [no.] 5 - Parts: Violin 2, June 10, 1910; 2.